hello and welcome to English Learning
Hub
English listening test designed for A1
learners
[Music]
this test consists of 20 questions which
are divided into four parts I will give
you a short instruction at the beginning
of each part
before we get started take a pen and
paper so you can take notes while
listening
are you ready let's get started
part one listen to four people talking
about what they did last summer and
answer the questions
last summer I plan to go to Italy with
some friends I booked everything and
then two days before the holiday I was
driving home from work and I was in a
bad car accident I had to stay in
hospital for two weeks oh it was
terrible my friends were having a great
time on the beach and I was lying in bed
last summer I went on two holidays a
family holiday to the beach and a
walking holiday with my friend Brad
the family holiday wasn't easy my kids
wanted to play while my wife and I were
trying to relax
the weather was great so they wanted to
be at the beach all the time
it was so tiring
my walking holiday was so much easier
we walked miles every day and it rained
a lot but it was peaceful and fun and
brat was great company
we went on a family holiday to South
Africa Last Summer
it was expensive but my children are
adults now so this will probably be our
last family holiday
my son wanted to Surf so we spent time
at the beach
we swam and relaxed while he surfed my
daughter wanted to enjoy The Nightlife
so she went out to bars in the evenings
while we went to quiet restaurants and
all stayed at the hotel
then we all went on a safari it was a
great holiday everyone did what they
liked
last summer I went on a sailing holiday
in Spain With Friends
the first week was great we swam had
picnics on quiet beaches and went
fishing and in the evenings we visited
bars but the second week wasn't so good
some guys wanted to bring girls to the
boat for parties but my friend Michael
and I wanted to sleep
we argued a lot
in the end Michael and I left the boat
and stayed at a guest house
choose the correct option
[Music]
foreign
listen to Karen describing life in Paris
and complete the sentences
so Karen what's it like living in Paris
oh it's very different from San
Francisco
the first thing you notice is the
clothes
I prefer to dress casually even when I'm
teaching but I can't do that in Paris
my students are businessmen and they're
always really well dressed so now I have
some formal clothes that I only use for
work
the worst thing is that clothes are
really expensive there
is your French good
it's pretty good now I'm taking lessons
and I can have conversations
it's a beautiful language but I don't
always understand what people say
because my French isn't perfect
what are the people like
some people say that people in Paris
aren't very friendly but it's the same
in New York City some people are
friendly and some aren't
my neighbors Jean-Luc and Marie are
really nice
I met them on the day I moved into my
apartment and now I have dinner with
them every weekend
that's lucky because you aren't a very
good cook
well fortunately there are lots of great
restaurants in Paris and the food is
fantastic and it's cheaper to eat out
there
one thing that surprised me though is
that there are a lot of fast food
restaurants and most of the customers
aren't foreign tourists they're French
so it's a myth that all French people
eat healthily
what's driving like in France
well I don't really use my car very much
but I think most French people drive
well
one or two of my friends don't though
my boyfriend always drives fast even on
little streets
he uses his phone when he's driving and
he shouts at other drivers
it's safer to walk than travel in a car
with John
oh my poor you
choose the correct option
[Music]
foreign
listen to five people talking about how
they use computers and match the
sentence halves
speaker one
I retired six months ago and my son
bought me a computer
I took a class so I could learn how to
use it
I don't use it every day
I don't like sending emails I prefer to
write letters
but I do buy quite a lot of things on
the internet like food and books
it's very easy to find what you want and
the best thing for me is that I don't
have to carry anything home
speaker two
some of my friends think I'm really
strange because I don't have a computer
at home
I do know how to use a computer I'm a
travel agent so I have to use one in my
job but I don't want one in my house
I don't like playing computer games and
I prefer to do my shopping downtown so I
can see what I'm buying
speaker three
I spend around four or five hours every
evening on my computer
I use it to write essays for college but
mostly I play computer games check my
Facebook account to see what my friends
are doing or download movies to watch
it's really easy to find new movies and
it's cheaper than going to the theater
speaker four
the internet is great isn't it
my daughter lives in Mexico she teaches
English there and it's really expensive
to call her on my home phone
but now we have Skype and we talk to
each other two or three times a week
she has two sons and they sometimes make
video calls to me
it's great to see and hear them
speaker five
I work at home and I use my computer all
day
I'm a reporter so I use the internet to
find out information when I'm writing an
article and I have an email account
which I use to send work to the
newspaper
but I don't just use my computer for
work
I like to watch TV on my laptop and I'm
always emailing my family and friends
I write around 30 emails a day
I also have a Twitter account and a Blog
that I use every day to tell people
about my life
choose the correct option
[Music]
thank you
foreign
listen to a radio interview and take
notes
good evening and welcome to celebrity
interview
I'm Sarah Johnson and my guest tonight
is Hollywood movie star James Brown
Welcome to New York James
thanks Sarah I'm really happy to be here
is this your first visit to New York
James
yes it is
and I'm having a great time here
everyone is so friendly
now James you've recently finished a new
film called going home
what's it about
well it's the story of a 15 year old boy
who argues with his parents
he has a difficult life but he gets a
job and goes to college and becomes a
teacher
when he's 25 he decides to go back and
see his parents at Christmas
so this is a movie for Christmas
that's right
it's very different from your last three
films which were about vampires
yes but it was time to do something
different
are you making another movie at the
moment
no I'm writing a book for children
how did that happen
well I got married three years ago and
we recently had a baby girl
I wanted to do something for my daughter
is it easy to write a children's book
actually it's really difficult
but I studied English in college and I
worked on a children's magazine for two
years before I became an actor so I have
some experience
well thank you for coming to talk to me
and good luck with the movie and the new
book
thank you too
choose the correct option
thank you
[Music]
foreign
don't forget to share your score in the
comments section
if you haven't taken our previous
listening tests yet I've pasted the
links in the description below and don't
forget to subscribe because more
valuable content is on the way
see you in the next videos